# Wang Xiaotao

# <Senior Front-End Engineer>

#### Profile

Email: wxt2005@gmail.com Location: Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China mainland

GitHub: https://github.com/wxt2005 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wxt2005

#### About me

I have 5 years of experience in developing complex web applications, collaborating with both small and large teams, and can pick up new tech stacks whenever it's necessary.

Have faith in the Internet, and willing to build products for a better and happier world.

### Experience

### Cainiao Network (August 2017 - Present)

Cainiao Smart Logistics Network Limited is a Chinese logistics company launched by Alibaba Group.

#### **Phoenix**

A massive operating management system for Cainiao's new subsidiary Danniao.

Led a team of four members to support the whole project.

Built a multi-entry web application.

Introduced React hooks for logic reusing and CSS grid for page layout.

Developed a React UI component library based on Antd. Used Storybook for UI development and documentation.

### Poststation Retail / Poststation Group-buying / Poststation Sample-sending

Three E-commerce services for helping Cainiao poststation owners increase profit.

Built three single page applications from scratch.

Abstracted three separate parts for better maintainability: shopping, payment and order management. All services only have different shopping page, shared the same payment and order management page.

Adopted Redux-Observable for clear asynchronous action management.

Built payment-related features, introduced Jest for unit testing.

Used modular CSS to prevent class name conflict and makes styles easy to maintain.

Standardized JavaScript code style by introducing ESLint.

#### Cainiao Box

Cainiao Box is a hardware product for customers to receive packages while not at home.

Built Cainiao Box Android app from scratch, wrote it with Java.

Implemented QR scan feature on top of ZXing.

Implemented Bluetooth communication protocol between Android phone and the box device.

#### Front-end infrastructure

Maintained front-end assets publishing system.

Developed a Word-to-HTML converting service based on Pandoc.

Implemented notification feature for the cloud building process.

### DXY (October 2014 - August 2017)

DXY is an online community for physicians, health care professionals, pharmacies and facilities.

#### Insight

Insight is a medicine database targeting Chinese pharmaceutical factories.

The front-end team leader of Insight, led a team of three members.

Refactored Insight from a legacy monolithic PHP codebase to a React + Redux application, leveraging the latest tools such as Webpack.

For preserving the ability to change page layout dynamically, designed a JSON schema for the back-end to control rendering.

#### DXY BBS & DXY App

DXY BBS is the biggest online forum for medical discussion in China, and DXY App is the iOS/Android version of it.

Refactored DXY BBS from a legacy monolithic Java codebase to a modular jQuery application. Used Gulp for building and Require.js for module loading.

Implemented an editor plugin for annotating uploaded images on top of darkroomjs.

Developed and maintained all post detail pages in DXY app's webview.

Collaborated with native engineers to design JS bridge for communicating between the web page and native app.

#### Front-end infrastructure

Developed a utility for opening native Apps from mobile web pages. Made use of Custom Scheme in Android, and Universal Link in iOS.

Developed a utility for compressing images before uploading from mobile web pages, in the sake of fast uploading and bandwidth saving.

## Side Projects

### **Browser Opener**

A Mac app to help you maintain browser preference.

As a front-end engineer, I like to use Chrome as a dev tool in daily work, however, my favorite browser in MacOS is Safari. So I have developed Browser Opener, which can help you decide which browser to open automatically when you clicked an external link.

This application was written in Swift, and could be found on Mac App Store. The Product Hunt page of this project has achieved the 3rd position of release day.

Mac App Store Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/browseropener/id1387480496

Product Hunt Page: https://www.producthunt.com/posts/browseropener

### Bangumi List

A website collecting Japanese anime watch lists.

There has been a lot of Japanese anime come to Chinese video websites since 2013. But due to fragmentation of copyrights, it was hard to watch them on one single website. That's why I started this project.

This website is also my playground of front-end technologies. It was first written in plain HTML tables, and then be refactored to Angular, then jQuery, and finally React. I'm recently considering making it to a Progress Web Application.

Site Link: https://bgmlist.com

### Skills

- JavaScript
- React + Redux
- Node.js

- HTML
- Vue + Vuex
- Java

- CSS and pre-processors
- jQuery
- Swift

# Certificate

- Qualification Certificate of Computer and Software Technology Proficiency Programmer
- Japanese-Language Proficiency Test N2
- College English Test CET-6

# Education

B.E. Civil Engineering -- Zhejiang Shuren University 2009-2013